It's been a long time, Mr. Yashiro.
I didn't expect you to get here first,
Satoru.
I've come to end this once and for all.
And I was getting everything ready
to kill you.
Just as I thought,
you've regained your memories
and intuition.
I'm surprised.
You realized I would use the cell phone,
something that didn't exist
when you were my student.
But just in case,
I had an analog backup.
It seems that one
was a little more effective.
In any case...
you're here too soon
considering your legs.
In my calculation,
she would show up
right after I set my trap,
and then you would arrive shortly after.
Yet as things are...
you're outside the trap,
and I'm inside it.
How did you do it?
You were never going to kill Kumi,
were you?
-You were after me from the start.
-No.
I planned this intending to kill her.
However,
I also had faith that you would stop me.
I mean, the only person
worth killing to me is you,
the one who fights to keep others alive.
That glint in your eye that
you always have
when facing the impossible.
I've witnessed it
countless times in the past,
and how you've achieved success
each time.
And now... your eyes are telling me this.
That you will overcome this, as well.
Tell me, Satoru.
What is the truth behind...
that glint in your eye?
The answer is rather simple and obvious.
If you sensed something in my eyes...
then that is...
a will to follow through.
The resolve to step forward.
What keeps me going
are the many words given to me
by the people I hold dear.
They've saved me, encouraged me,
and pushed me.
They taught me that you can't open
a new door without moving forward.
Wanting to fill the void inside yourself.
These words did the same for me.
Both when I was a kid,
and even after I woke up.
They gave me the power to take action.
You said the same thing that day
in the car 17 years ago.
When I heard you say those words
as a grade school kid,
I was honestly surprised.
I'm sure you were.
That's because...
they're the words I heard from you
when I graduated from grade school.
They're your own words, Mr. Yashiro.
I've been a fifth-grader three times now.
And this is my second time living in 2005.
I... I've relived the past
a number of times now.
Do you believe me?
I do... Satoru.
Even if I wanted to deny it...
there are so many things it would explain.
It all makes sense now.
You also said this:
That courageous actions
shouldn't end in tragedy.
I believe that... I was able to regain
so many things because of these words.
So, Mr. Yashiro,
why don't we end things here.
Satoru...
am I evil?
No, I know.
That's how the world would measure me.
But...
are society's principles in the right?
Aren't they just a fabrication
so those who deny
their deepest desires can show
that they are good people?
I judge my actions by my own measure...
and justify them.
Satoru.
You're right.
Let's end things here.
STAFF
The last thing for me to do,
is to end this all
with both of our deaths.
I...
I reject being punished by a worldview
I don't accept.
And, Satoru...
what you will get
in exchange for your life,
is my end...
in the form of my death.
You won't get any of that.
I haven't given you an answer
to your first question.
The reason I was able to get here
so quickly.
It's something my doctor told me.
He said that that the power
of the human will...
can defy medical explanation.
Satoru! Satoru!
You did good.
Both of you.
I've been wanting Satoru to wake up
ever since that day.
What?
My actions, my thoughts...
Satoru was the only one
who ever understood me.
And after Satoru
fell into his coma, I've...
I really became alone.
I asked myself
what I was supposed to do next.
The answer was very simple.
I would stay near Satoru
and continue to watch over him.
And so you even became a city councilman.
And on that day...
When Satoru finally awoke...
I was so happy...
I couldn't stop crying.
I wasn't...
I wasn't alone anymore.
When I saw Satoru moving...
my heart was filled with an exuberance
I hadn't felt for over 10 years.
That's why I took action.
All in order...
All in order to end, with my own hands,
Satoru...
the only boy I wasn't able to kill.
So, you admit that you
intended to kill him?
Yes.
Of course!
CHIBA SERIAL MURDERS
NISHIZONO SENTENCED TO DEATH
Come in.
Satoru.
Hi.
Have a seat.
Thanks for making time for me.
I'll always make time for you
if you want to hear about Yashiro.
I heard his death sentence was finalized.
Yeah.
Yashiro was guilty of over
30 murders in total.
Most were past the statute of limitations,
but we were able to charge him for
the eight murders
and attempted murders in Chiba.
He confessed to all of them.
The time
taken from you and those falsely accused
can never be returned.
But...
even if it's just a little,
I think we were able to ease your pain.
Thank you, Satoru.
I'm proud that I was able to
be by your side.
Kenya...
And also...
I'm sorry, Satoru.
It's my fault your part in this
cost you so much.
-I--
-I don't feel like it has.
I was the one that was saved.
I should be the one thanking you.
I was able to step forward
because I had you by my side.
Thank you, Kenya.
Do you think
we came close to becoming heroes?
It certainly wasn't all pretty,
but I'd like to believe we have.
MIKOTO ELEMENTARY ESSAYS
RESOLVE - BY KENYA KOBAYASHI
I'M GOING TO SAVE THE PEOPLE
I WASN'T ABLE TO.
TOGETHER WITH MY FRIENDS.
THAT'S WHAT I RESOLVE TO DO.
A CITY WHERE ONLY I AM GONE
MY HERO
BY SATORU FUJINUMA
My favorite manga comic Wonder Guy
was made into a TV show.
Wonder Guy had been fighting alone,
but with a trusting heart as his weapon,
he made more friends.
I also want to make many friends
that I can trust,
and who can trust me.
Following Wonder Guy's example,
even if I fail, I won't give up.
I can try again and again.
Until I can finally succeed.
Wonder Guy's words
give me strength.
I want to become a manga author
and create a hero like that, too.
THE WORLD KING OF FLAMES
BY SATORU FUJINUMA
SATORU FUJINUMA
"NEO CENTURY YUKI"
I'm going to step out
to work on the storyboard.
Okay. Leave this to us.
Bye!
It's cold out there today!
Oh, hello, Mr. Urata.
What?! Where's Mr. Fujinuma?
-He's out working on the storyboard.
-What, he's not here?!
Come on, I splurged on these
because we just got picked up
for an anime adaptation.
Really?!
Yes! And we're going to be
the tentpole for 2012!
We made it, everyone!
That's awesome!
Yes!
-Yeah!
-Mr. Fujinuma is going to be a mogul now!
Let's drink!
No, not yet! You can't!
Especially not you!
-Why not?
-Remember how bad you got last time?
So, definitely not you!
Not even when Mr. Fujinuma gets back.
-You just stick to water.
-Okay, fine.
Good. Okay, so let's hide it all
and keep it a surprise.
Let's hide all this,
and start by having everyone look
a little gloomy first.
-Okay.
-Let's go with that.
Satoru,
you're living your dream.
I bought these!
Not you!
I haven't experienced a Revival
since I woke up.
It must be because this moment
is the real timeline.
I can tell that the memories from my
first timeline when I never fell asleep
are starting to fade.
The 15 years I've been asleep...
I was never alone.
I had friends who filled in
the blank spaces.
Nothing made me prouder than that.
And it shines brightly inside my heart.
The city where only I am gone.
I treasure nothing more
than the time I spent there.
The city where only I am gone.
It's really coming down!
It's crazy, right?
Could I join you until the snow passes?
The snow blankets the scenery in white.
The future has been turned blank.
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto